Guide to the Buildings Constructed for Yale University's Bicentennial Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Buildings constructed for Yale University's bicentennial photographs
1901-1963
RU 697
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
The materials consist of photographs of buildings constructed for the Yale bicentennial. The bulk of the collection documents the University Dining Hall and Woolsey Hall. One photograph documents construction in 1901.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs of buildings constructed for the Yale bicentennial. The bulk of the collection documents the University Dining Hall and Woolsey Hall. One photograph documents construction in 1901.
College buildings; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Transparencies; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Anniversaries, etc.; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Centennial celebrations, etc.
- Photographs, Series I
  - Aerial views (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - View from Hewitt Quadrangle, 1902 - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2 - 5)
  - Views from College and Grove Streets at intersection (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Memorial Hall
    - Views from Hewitt Quadrangle (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Views from College and Grove Streets at intersection (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Interior (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interior, Civil War Memorial (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Interior, President's Room (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - University Dining Hall
    - Construction views (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1901-1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Dining Hall & Alumni War memorial, -1927 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
    - Colonnade, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Interior, 1902-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Interior, 1930- (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Interior, kitchen, 1937, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Woolsey Hall
    - Exterior (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Interior, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Interior, 1916- (Box 1, Folder 23 - 24)
    - Interior, Newberry Organ console and organists (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Interior, concert series (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Architect's drawings (prints of)
    - General, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Proposed administration building addition, Circa 1927 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Oversize, 10:13 Commons and Woolsey Hall (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Slides (Box 3)
  - Transparencies (Box 4)
  - Folio, Signed etching by Louis Orr (Box DR25F81)